Sigma Pi Phi, Beta Psi Boul; Records apap333
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Sigma Pi Phi, Beta Psi Boulé Records1983-2015
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Sigma Pi Phi, Beta Psi Boulé
apap333
9.92 cubic ft. plus digital contents of CDs and floppy disk
The Sigma Pi Phi, Beta Psi Boulé Records document the history and day-to-day operations of the Beta Psi Boulé. A professional fraternity, Sigma Pi Phi was founded on May 15, 1904 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and its members are distinguished African American men with college and graduate degrees. Beta Psi is the fraternity’s 69th Boulé founded on May 5, 1984 in the Capital District of New York.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of official meeting minutes of the organization located in Series 1.
Acquisition Information
Sigma Pi Phi, Beta Psi Boulé donated all of the materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives beginning in November 2012. The organization donated additional records in 2013, 2014 and 2015.
Administrative History
Sigma Pi Phi, Beta Psi Boulé is the Capital District’s chapter of the nation’s oldest Greek-letter organization comprised of college-educated and professional African American men. Founded in Philadelphia on May 15, 1904, the Sigma Pi Phi fraternity is referred to as the Boulé which is Greek for a council of noblemen. Its members are called Archons and their wives are Archousia. As of 2012, Sigma Pi Phi had over 5,000 members in 129 "chapters", known as member Boulés, throughout the United States, the United Kingdom and the Bahamas. A secret society, Sigma Pi Phi has begun to release information about itself to the public, however, it still holds to confidentiality within the organization.
The national office is the Grand Boulé with five regional Boulés to represent the Northeast, Southeast, Central, Western, and Pacific regions with individual Boulés within each. Sigma Pi Phi’s elected executive officers are referred to by Greek titles. The local Boulé head is the Sire Archon, and there is a Sire Archon-Elect, and an Immediate Past Sire Archon. The Grammateus is the executive secretary, the Thesauristes is the treasurer, the Rhetoricus arranges meetings and programs, the Agogos heads the constitution and by-laws committee and the Grapter is the official news reporter of the Boulé in charge of news and editorial duties. The Grand Boulé's elected executive officers are Grand Officers with the title Grand before their post and the regional Boulés' elected executive officers have the respective Region added before the position title. For example, Northeast Region Sire Archon would be the head of the Northeast Region.
The Beta Psi Boulé of the Capital Region was established on May 5, 1984. It has been active in and supportive of the Capital District community for more than a quarter century hosting annual community events, supporting charitable initiatives for various causes and sponsoring endowments directly from Beta Psi or from the Sigma Pi Phi Foundation. The University at Albany Spellman Achievement Award is a Beta Psi scholarship endowment created in honor of the late Seth Spellman Jr., one of the founders of the Beta Psi Boulé. The members of Beta Psi are high ranking officials in the Capital District community, including faculty and administrators in area Universities, business owners and other professionals with postgraduate educations and titles.
The current Sire Archon of Beta Psi Boulé is Dr. Levester Cannon. Former Sire Archons include:
Scope and Contents
The Sigma Pi Phi, Beta Psi Boulé Records document the history of the Capital District’s chapter of the nation’s oldest Greek-letter organization comprised of college-educated and professional African American men. The collection contains Sigma Pi Phi, Beta Psi charter certificates, administrative records including meeting agendas and minutes, notices, correspondences and financial reports, the Northeast Regional and Grand Boulé conference materials, photographs, subject files, executive committee records, and Sigma Pi Phi's official publication The Boulé Journal.
The collection also includes records of Beta Psi community involvement and contributions to the Capital Region, member achievements and recognition, annual events and articles of memorabilia. The collection covers the years of existence of the Beta Psi Boulé, from 1984 – 2014 with the exception of the years 1991 and 2010. There is a nearly complete run of the publication The Boulé Journal, however, there are no issues for 1989.
The archivist transferred all files on CD and floppy disk to the department's server.
Separated Materials
Archivists transferred the two volume monograph The History of Sigma Pi Phi: First of the African-American Greek-Letter Fraternities by Charles Wesley and Hobart Sidney Jarrett, to the book division of Special Collections. The catalogue record for the monograph will be included in Minerva, the University Library Catalog.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 and 4 are arranged chronologically. Series 2 and Series 3 are arranged alphabetically.
African Americans and Civil Rights Organizations; Albany, New York; African Americans--Education (Higher); African American Greek letter societies; African American fraternal organizations; African American college graduates--New York (State)--Albany (N.Y.); Albany (N.Y.); By-laws (administrative records); Constitutions; Ritual Objects; Charters; Administrative records; Minutes (administrative records); Agendas (administrative records); Newsletters; Financial Records; Membership lists; Press Releases; Correspondence; Programs (documents); Photographs; Sigma Pi Phi, Beta Psi Boulé; Sigma Pi Phi
- Administration, 1984-2015; 1; 2.0 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the Beta Psi Boulé’s administrative records. The materials cover the beginning of the charter process for the Beta Psi Boulé to present day. The files consist of the Boulé’s day-to-day administrative records for 1984-2015 with the exception of the years 1991 and 2010. The series consists of charter plans, certificates and reports, administrative records, Beta Psi Executive Committee documents, financial reports, general meeting minutes, correspondences, memorandums, notices and agendas as well as documents from some of the Boulé’s committees. The bulk of the documents were created by the officers and members of Beta Psi Boulé and the officers of the Grand Boulé with the exception of some correspondence and event brochures of other Greek letter fraternities and sororities, Capital District businesses and charitable organizations.
  As the majority of administrative records were created by the executive committee of the fraternity, please note that these officers are elected by the members of the Boulé every two years. This change in record creators and keepers is reflected in the way meeting packets are arranged year by year. Beta Psi had its fewest members immediately after it received its charter. Therefore the first few years of administrative records are filed into single folders by the creator. As the Boulé grew and officers changed, record keeping changed in the way the materials were created, distributed and retained. Some years' agendas were sent out with notices, financial reports were stored with meeting minutes, and executive and general meetings were kept together. In other years, the agendas and meeting minutes are together. Most recently, minutes, agendas, and financial reports all have their own folders. The archivist retained this original order for all years.
  The transformation of the official Beta Psi header and the Sigma Pi Phi insignia can be mapped over the years by the documents in this series.
  - Charter, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 1)
  - Administrative Records - [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 2)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - Administrative Records - [RESTRICTED], 1985 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 3)
  - Administrative Records - [RESTRICTED], 1986 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 4)
  - Administrative Records - [RESTRICTED], 1987 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 5)
  - Administrative Records - [RESTRICTED], 1988 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 7)
  - Financial Reports, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 8)
  - Meeting Minutes and Notices - [RESTRICTED], 1989 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 10)
  - Meeting Minutes and Notices - [RESTRICTED], 1990 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 11)
  - Administrative Records - [RESTRICTED], 1992 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 12)
  - Administrative Records - [RESTRICTED], 1993 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 14)
  - Financial Reports, 1994 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 15)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 1994 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 16)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 1995 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 18)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 1996 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 20)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 1997 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 22)
  - Financial Reports, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 23)
  - Meeting Minutes and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 1998 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 25)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, 1999 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 26)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 1999 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 27)
  - Meeting Notices and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 1999 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 28)
  - Correspondence and Memos, 2000 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 29)
  - Financial Reports, 2000 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 30)
  - Meeting Minutes and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 2000 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 32)
  - Executive Committee Minutes and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 33)
  - Financial Reports, 2001 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 34)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 35)
  - Meeting Notices and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 36)
  - Memos, 2001 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 37)
  - Social Action Committee, 2001 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 39)
  - Executive Committee Minutes and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 2002 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 40)
  - Financial Reports, 2002 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 41)
  - Forms, 2002 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 42)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 2002 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 43)
  - Meeting Notices and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 2002 (Box 1 (1-Administration), Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 2003 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 2)
  - Executive Committee Notices and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 2003 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 3)
  - Financial Reports, 2003 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 4)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 2003 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 5)
  - Meeting Notices and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 2003 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Documents, 2003 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 7)
  - 20th Anniversary, 2004 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 9)
  - Executive Committee Minutes and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 2004 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 10)
  - Financial Reports, 2004 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 11)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 2004 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 12)
  - Meeting Notices and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 2004 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 13)
  - Meeting Planning CD Project, 2004 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 14)
  - Memos, 2004 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 15)
  - Boulé Golf Committee, 2005 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 16)
  - Correspondence and Memos, 2005 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 17)
  - Executive Committee Minutes and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 2005 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 18)
  - Financial Reports, 2005 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 19)
  - Meeting Agendas, 2005 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 20)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 2005 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 21)
  - Meeting Notices, 2005 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 2006 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 23)
  - Executive Committee Agendas, 2006 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 24)
  - Executive Committee Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 2006 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 25)
  - Financial Reports, 2006 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 26)
  - Meeting Agendas, 2006 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 27)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 2006 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 28)
  - Memos, 2006 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 29)
  - Strategic Plan, 2006 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 30)
  - Committee Reports, 2007 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 2007 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 32)
  - Executive Committee - [RESTRICTED], 2007 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 33)
  - Financial Reports, 2007 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 34)
  - Boulé Foundation Receipts, 2008 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 2008 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 36)
  - Executive Committee - [RESTRICTED], 2008 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 37)
  - Financial Reports, 2008 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 38)
  - Meeting Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 2008 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 39)
  - Social Action Committee, 2008 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 40)
  - Bank Account Transfer - [RESTRICTED], 2009 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 2009 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 42)
  - Executive Committee, 2009 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 43)
  - Meeting Minutes and Agendas - [RESTRICTED], 2009 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 2011 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 45)
  - Financial Reports, 2011 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 46)
  - Meeting Agenda, 2011 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 47)
  - Financial Reports, 2012 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 48)
  - Report on Archives at SUNY Albany, 2012 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 49)
  - Ad Hoc Committee, 2013 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 50)
  - Business Meeting Agenda, 2013 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 51)
  - Executive Committee Minutes - [RESTRICTED], 2013 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 52)
  - Financial Reports, 2013 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 53)
  - Meeting Packets - [RESTRICTED], 2013 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 54)
  - Financial Reports, 2014 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 55)
  - Meeting Packets - [RESTRICTED], 2014 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 56)
  - Financial Reports, 2015 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 57)
  - Meeting Packets - [RESTRICTED], 2015 (Box 2 (1-Administration), Folder 56)
- Subject Files, 1984-2015; Undated; 2; 3.02 cubic ft.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains records of Beta Psi Annual Membership reports to the Grand Boulé, Christmas is for the Archousai and other annual events, some social action committee documents for specific community initiatives and interests (minutes and agendas for the committee can be found in Series 1 - Administration), Boulé Foundation and Beta Psi charitable initiative documents, and the creation and arrangement of the University at Albany Spellman Achievement Award, a scholarship program endowed by Beta Psi in honor of the late Seth Spellman Jr., a founders of the Beta Psi Boulé. The series also includes records of events sponsored or supported by the Beta Psi Boulé, documents from the nominating committee later renamed the Membership Council, revised constitutions, by-laws, and rituals of the fraternity and a Sigma Pi Phi protocol manual.
  - American Association For Affirmative Action, Regional Director Gavel, Undated (Artifact-box 1)
  - Annual Events, 1996; 1998-2002; 2005-2006; 2013-2015 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Annual Events: Christmas, 1990; 1992-1993; 1997-1998 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Annual Events: Christmas, 1999-2006; 2011-2013 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Annual Events: Christmas, 2014 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 4-5)
  - Annual Events: Christmas Party Photographs, 2004 (Cd 1)
  - Annual Events: Christmas Party Photographs, 2014 (Cd 4)
  - Annual Events: Photograph Albums, Undated (Oversized 1)
  - Annual Events: Negative Film Strips, Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Annual Events: Photos, Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Annual Membership Reports, 1985-2007 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 8-9)
  - Beta Psi Active Roster, 1992-2000; Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Beta Psi Banner, Undated (Oversized 2)
  - Beta Psi Delegates to the Grand Boulé, 1986; 1988; 2002 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Beta Psi Endowments and the Boulé Foundation, 1988-2011 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Beta Psi Foundation Scholarship Award, Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Beta Psi Member Name Stickers, Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Beta Psi Member Recognition, the University at Albany, 2007; 2012 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Beta Psi Membership Directory, 2001-2002; 2005-2006 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Boulé News, 1990; 1993; 2000-2003; 2006; Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 17-18)
  - A Celebration of Life for Lawrence Cornelius Burwell, Jr., 2001 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Conference Planning Guidelines, 2004 (Floppy-disk 1)
  - Establishment of New Subordinate Boulés, 1984-2005 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Grammateus Guides, 1998-2000 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 21-22)
  - Grand Sire Archon Nominees, 1990-2005; Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Heritage, John, Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - March on Washington, Maurice Thornton, 2013 (Dvd 1)
  - Membership Directory and By-Laws, 2013 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Membership Directory and Lists, 2009-2011 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Membership Council/Nominating Committee, 1984-2011; Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 27-30)
  - New York State Martin Luther King, Jr. Commission and Institute for Nonviolence: Certificate of Appreciation, 1993-1994 (Oversized 3)
  - Northeast Region Best Practices Guide (folders 1-2 of 3), 2008 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 31-32)
  - Northeast Region Best Practices Guide (folder 3 of 3), 2008 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Revised Rituals Manual, 1997 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Rituals, 1984; Undated (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Sigma Pi Phi Beta Psi Boulé Files, 1997; 1999-2004 (Cd 2)
    The files were compiled by the Beta Psi Boulé for archival use and contain records created from 1997 to 2004. The original order of the files was kept since the creator grouped many related files into folders. The files include records of the 15th Regional Conference, the Beta Nu Conference web materials, Beta Psi administrative records, documents from the Seth Spellman Fund, Boulé graphics, photographs, programs and lists from annual events, rituals, and constitutions and by-laws.
  - Sigma Pi Phi Beta Psi Boulé Constitution and By-Laws, 1999; Undated (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Sigma Pi Phi Beta Psi Boulé Stationaries, Undated (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Sigma Pi Phi Constitution and By-Laws, 1985; 1990; 1992; 1996 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Sigma Pi Phi Constitution and By-Laws Member Binders, 1985; 1992 (Artifact-box 2)
  - Sigma Pi Phi Fraternity, A Guide for Implementing the Fraternity's Strategic Plan, 2010 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Sigma Pi Phi Protocol Manual, 2010 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Dr. Leonard A. Slade, Jr., 2000; 2002-2003; 2012-2015; Undated (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Dr. Leonard A. Slade, Jr., 2013 (Flat-file 1)
  - Dr. Leonard Slade, Jr., Poems from God put a Rainbow in the Sky, University at Albany Alumni House, 2014 (Dvd 2)
  - Social Action Programs of Delta Theta Boulé, Las Vegas, Nevada, Undated (Dvd 3)
  - Soirée, 2013 (Dvd 4)
  - Soirée, including Times Union Article about Beta Psi Boulé, 2013 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Sponsored Events (folder 1 of 2), 1993; 1998-2001; 2003-2005; 2011 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Sponsored Events (folder 2 of 2), 1993; 1998-2001; 2003-2005; 2011 (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Sponsored Events: The Jackie Wilson Story, ca. 2003 (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Statement of Activities, 2004-2007 (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Dr. Connie Styles - 80th, 2014 (Dvd 5)
  - Thirtieth Anniversary Celebration, Beta Psi Boulé, 2014 (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Thirtieth Anniversary Celebration, Beta Psi Boulé, 2014 (Dvd 7)
  - Thirtieth Anniversary Celebration, Beta Psi Boulé Commemorative Pen, 2014 (Artifact-box 2)
    Archon Ray Walker presented each Archon in the Beta Psi Boulé with one of these pens.
  - Thornton, Dr. Maurice, 2015 (Flat-file 5)
  - Dr. Maurice Thornton Review of The Butler: a Witness to History, Friends of the Albany Public Library, 2014 (Dvd 6)
  - Times Union Article on Death of Maya Angelou Featuring Dr. Leonard A. Slade, Jr., 2014 (Flat-file 3)
  - Transfers, 2001-2002; Undated (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Tribute to Virgil Hall Hodges, 2014 (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - University at Albany Department of Africana Studies, 2014; Undated (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - University at Albany Department of Africana Studies Accolades Advertisement Featuring Dr. Leonard Slade, 2013 (Flat-file 4)
  - University at Albany Department of Africana Studies, Commencement Recognition Program, 2014 (Dvd 8)
  - University at Albany President Robert Jones, Capital Region Conversation, 2014 (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Youth Development and Creative Leadership Program Handbook, Kappa Boulé, 1989-1991 (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 9)
- Special Events, 1985-2011; 3; 1.9 cubic ft.
  The Special Events series contains records of the Biennial Boulé meetings and conferences for the Northeast Region and some of the Grand Boulé conferences attended by members of the Beta Psi Boulé. The bulk of the series are the 13th – 19th Biennial Northeast Regional Conferences from 1999 – 2011, and Beta Psi Regional Planning Committees' records from planning and facilitating the 15th Biennial Regional Conference in 2003. The series also contains records from the Northeast Region Executive Committee as well as some documents pertaining to the Northeast Regional Conferences of 1985 – 1990.
  - 13th Biennial Northeast Regional Conference, 1999 (Box 1 (3-Special Events), Folder 1)
  - 14th Biennial Northeast Regional Conference, 2001-2003 (Box 1 (3-Special Events), Folder 2-3)
  - 15th Biennial Northeast Regional Conference: Banquet Event Orders, 2002-2003 (Box 1 (3-Special Events), Folder 4)
  - 15th Biennial Northeast Regional Conference: Mailings and Program, 2003 (Box 1 (3-Special Events), Folder 5)